It's also important to decide how we
我们还需要
define when two stocks are diverging from there spread.
定义两支股票价差何时出现了偏离
For this, we want to choose a threshold.
我们需要设定一个阈值
If the spread exceeds the threshold,
如果价差超过阈值
then we can assume that the spread is
那么我们认为价差是暂时的
temporary and will revert back to its historical mean.
将回到历史均值上
We can have two kinds of thresholds.
我们可以设置两种阈值
One threshold, tells us that the spread is much wider than its historical average.
一个阈值告诉我们价差比历史平均值宽多了
Another threshold, can tell us that the spread is
另一个阈值告诉我们价差
much narrower than its historical average.
比历史平均值窄多了
When the spread is unusually wide,
当价差异常宽时
the action we take is called shorting the spread.
我们将做空价差
We say we're shorting the spread,
这么做的原因是
because we expect the spread to get smaller in the future.
我们预计价差在未来将变小
Conversely, when the spread is unusually narrow,
相反 当价差异常窄时
the action we take is called going long the spread.
我们将做多价差
We say we're going long the spread or buying
这么做的原因是
the spread because we expect the spread to get larger in the future.
我们预计价差在未来将变大
Let's discuss what it means to go long or short spread.
下面说说做多或做空价差是什么意思
When the spread widens,
当价差变宽时
we decide to short the spread.
我们决定做空价差
This means, that we short the asset that has increased relative to the spread.
也就是做空相对于价差来说上涨的资产
We also buy the asset that has declined relative to the spread.
并且买入相对于价差来说下跌的资产
Some of our previous examples involved shorting the spread.
之前的某些例子就是做空价差
Conversely, when we see this spread narrow,
相反 当我们看到这个价差变窄时
we decided to go long the spread.
我们决定做多价差
This means that we buy the asset that has declined relative to the spread.
也就是买入相对于价差来说下跌的资产
We also short the asset that has increased relative to the spread.
并且做空相对于价差来说上涨的资产
If this concept sounds a bit confusing,
如果这个概念听起来有点困惑的话
just to remember to buy low and sell high.
只需记住低买高卖
In other words, buy when it's on sale,
也就是说 当价格过低时 买入
and sell when it's overpriced.
当价格过高时 卖出
The way we define these thresholds,
定义阈值的方式是
is by calculating how many standard deviations the spread is from its historical average.
计算价差偏离历史平均值多少个标准差
This is called the Z-score of spread.
称为价差的 z 分数
A Z-score of positive one,
z 分数为 1 表示
means that a value is one standard deviation greater than its historical mean.
值比历史均值大一个标准差
To calculate the Z-score,
为了计算 z 分数
we subtracted the mean and divide by the standard deviation.
我们减去均值并除以标准差
As with all modeling,
与所有模型一样
is necessary to perform backtesting.
我们需要进行回溯测试
By backtesting, I mean that we want to test our model on historical data.
也就是用历史数据测试模型
We want to test in a way that simulates the model making predictions in real time.
我们需要模拟模型实时作出预测的情形
We don't want to expose the model to data that occurs in the future.
不能使模型暴露于发生在未来的数据
To perform backtesting, we divide our historical data into a training set,
为了进行回溯测试 我们将历史数据划分成
a validation set, and a test set.
训练集 验证集和测试集
The training set has earlier data up to a cutoff date,
训练集包含直到某个截止日期的历史数据
the validation set has data that occurs after
验证集包含从训练集之后
the training set up to and even later cutoff date,
到更靠后的截止日期的数据
the test set contains data that occurs after the validation set.
测试集包含在验证集之后的数据
We train our model on the training set,
我们用训练集训练模型
then do intermediate checks using the validation set.
然后中途使用验证集检查模型
This allows us to adjust our model to help it perform more accurate estimates.
这样便能够调整模型 使其估算结果更准确
When we've adjusted our model to the point that we think it's ready to use,
将模型调整到我们认为能够投入使用的状态后
we then check it against the test set to see if it really works.
我们用测试集检查模型 看看它是否真的可行
Note that, it's important not to use the test set until we're done optimizing the model.
在优化完模型之前 不能使用测试集
If we were to adjust the model after using the final test set,
如果在使用最终测试集之后还去调整模型
this would be like letting our model cheat by showing it information about the future.
就好像作弊了 因为我们向模型展示了未来的信息